JINBONG LEE, P.Eng.

94 Nolanhurst Rise NW, Calgary, AB T3R 0Z5 (403)818-1310

ib.lee@shaw.ca

SUMMARY

Over ten years of experience in the oil and gas industry as project engineer, mechanical engineer and various project management roles.

Experienced in project engineering management, mechanical engineering of static and packaged equipment, field engineering works, ABSA/CSA/AER approvals, proposals, engineering and construction interfaces, and various regulatory tasks.

Extensive knowledge and understanding of various work flows in FEED and EPC project. Registered in APEGA as a Professional Engineer.

EXPERTISE AND SKILLS

- Problem Resolution
- Project Management
- Auto CAD
- ASME B31.3
- CSA Z662 / B149.1~3
- Trouble Shooting
- Excellent Computer Skills MS-Project / Office
- Coreworx
- ASME Sec. VIII Div.1&2 Technical Documentation
 - CSA W47.1 / W59
 - NFPA 14

- FEED and EPC project
- ABSA Regulation
- PESR / CSA B51
- Alberta Building Code
- Regulatory Approvals

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Project Engineer, SK E&C, South Korea / Sunlake Co. Ltd., Calgary, AB 2013.05 ~ 2018.02 Fort Hills Mining Project, Secondary Extraction, Suncor Energy

- Managed engineering deliverables, schedules and man-hours during FEED and EPC Phases.
- Provided plans and developments, and coordinated reviews of engineering works.
- Worked with client, vendors and other disciplines to follow up project decisions, engineering issues and design deficiencies.
- Coordinated the meeting for PFD/P&ID, SOW, Plot Plan, HAZOP and 3D model reviews, and supported followed up to close out action items.
- Reviewed LDTs, ISO drawings, tie-in list, equipment list, PSV list, piping material specifications and building classifications.
- Reviewed regulatory requirements and provided submissions for AER, AENV, TC, RMWB, NavCanada, CNSC, ABSA and CSA approvals and authorizations.
- Reviewed and developed Engineering/Construction Work Packages.
- Provided project status, budgets, schedules, plans, and engineering progress reports.
- Performed technical advice, monitoring, supervision and support of mechanical designs, technical documentations, calculations including pressure equipment and piping in compliance with regulatory requirements, technical codes and standards.
- Reviewed specifications, data sheets, calculations, material requisitions, vendor drawings and documents for pressure equipment.
- Supported technical bid analysis and evaluation in the selection of equipment verification and approval.
- Troubleshoot field related issues requiring engineering decisions and provide recommendation for the solutions.
- Supported change management and PO close out.

Senior Project Engineer (Field), Sunlake Co. Ltd., Calgary, AB

2016.01 ~ 2018.01 Fort Hills Mining Project, Secondary Extraction, Suncor Energy

- Dispatched to construction site and performed field engineering works including regulatory compliance tasks and project interface activities.
- Performed engineering and construction interfaces and inter-discipline works with U&O, infrastructures, OPP, Electricity, Telecom, automation contractors, etc..
- Provided and developed the ABSA submissions for piping design registration and modification, closure weld approval, repair/alteration approval and design variance.
- Monitored and supervised engineering disciplines to ensure the compliance with regulation changes and amendments.
- Performed field review for building permit of pump houses and E-Houses with Building SCO, Fire SCO, Electrical SCO, and QMP coordinator.
- Coordinated and communicated with field engineering disciplines and other relevant teams to follow up field changes such as FCN, FDCN and CDCN.

Project Engineer, Aprogen KIC, South Korea

2008.09~2013.04 Mildred Lake Mining Replacement Project, Syncrude Kearl Expansion Project, Imperial Oil

- Performed project management roles for manufacturing surge bin and crushing facilities including project budgets, cost control, planning, and risk analysis.
- Managed engineering workflow for shop detailing and 3D model review.
- Performed RFI coordination of design and quality issue with vendors and clients.
- Involved in proposal and estimation for engineering and manufacturing of oil sand mining facilities such as Surge Bin, Crusher, and Primary Separation Cell.

Mechanical Engineer, Shinhan Machinery, South Korea

2005.03~2008.08 Iron & Steel Mill Industry Project, POSCO, South Korea

- Prepared and reviewed of mechanical design, engineering criteria, specifications, standards, and scope of work.
- Conducted design verification tasks for compliance to project procedures.
- Prepared and developed material requisitions, data sheets, design calculations for mechanical components of cokes moving machines.
- Supported preparation of commissioning and start-up procedures.

EDUCATION

1998-2005 Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering

Bachelor of Computer Systems Engineering

Chosun University, South Korea

ASSOCIATIONS

Registered as a Professional Engineer with APEGA (#216816)

REFERENCES

Available upon request.